Gerard P. Kuiper papers 1894-1992 (bulk 1949-1973)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Gerard P. Kuiper Papers
1894-1992,
(bulk 1949-1973)
MS 480
Kuiper, Gerard P. (Gerard Peter), 1905-1973
Gerard P. Kuiper Papers is comprised of the personal and professional papers of astronomer Gerard P. Kuiper. The bulk of the material relates to his career as an astronomical researcher and administrator at the Yerkes Observatory (University of Chicago), McDonald Observatory (University of Texas), and the Lunar Planetary Laboratory (University of Arizona). Items included in the collection are correspondence, publications, research material, newspaper clippings and photographs as well as Kuiper’s personal experience as a member of the ALSOS Mission following World War II.
103 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://www.library.arizona.edu/speccoll
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection
Biographical Note
Gerard P. Kuiper was born in The Netherlands in the town of Harenkarspel on December 7, 1905. He entered Leiden University in 1924 and received his Bachelor of Science in 1927. Kuiper immediately continued his graduate studies and received his Ph.D. in Astronomy in 1933. While completing his advanced studies, he was an assistant observer at the Leiden Observatory, 1928-1933. From 1933-1935 he was a Kellogg Fellow under American astronomer Robert Grant Aiken at Lick Observatory, Mount Hamilton, California.
In 1935 he went to Harvard College Observatory, Cambridge, Massachusetts as a lecturer in Astronomy. There he met Sara Parker Fuller and they married on June 20, 1936. They had two children, Paul Hayes born in 1941 and Sylvia Lucy Ann born in 1947. In 1936 Gerard Kuiper accepted a job at Yerkes Observatory of the University of Chicago as an assistant professor of Practical Astronomy. In 1937 he became an American citizen and was appointed associate professor. In 1943 he became a full professor and in 1947 Kuiper became the director of the Yerkes and McDonald Observatories. In 1960 he resigned from Yerkes Observatory and relocated to the University of Arizona in Tucson. Some of his best known discoveries during his tenure at the University of Chicago are: the atmosphere of Saturn's moon Titan in 1944, the carbon dioxide atmosphere of Mars in 1948, Uranus's satellite Miranda in 1948, and Neptune's satellite Nereid in 1949.
In 1960 Kuiper established the Lunar and Planetary Laboratory (LPL), first as part of the Institute of Atmospheric Physics and later as a separate unit at the University of Arizona. In his years at LPL Kuiper established a group of telescopes in the Santa Catalina Mountains above Tucson; made balloon spectroscopic observations of the Earth's atmosphere; and conducted observatory site surveys in Hawaii, Mexico, and California. He was principal investigator on the NASA Ranger program, and as an experimenter on the Surveyor programs in the mid 1960s. Kuiper also served on numerous NASA Committees and Panels and briefed many high government officials on features of the space program. He died on a vacation trip in Mexico City on December 24, 1973
Gerard P. Kuiper is considered by many as the father of modern planetary science. In 1975 Kuiper was posthumously honored by NASA when the airborne infrared telescope was named the “Kuiper Airborne Observatory”. He was honored again in 1984 with the establishment of the Kuiper Prize by the American Astronomical Society Division of Planetary Science, and in 1992 when the Kuiper Belt was named after him.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into 18 Series,
Series I: Personal Files, 1924-1973
Series II: Employment, 1933-1973
Series III: Correspondence, 1923-1974
Series IV: Lunar Planetary Laboratory (LPL),Telescopes and Facilities, 1960-1973
Series V: International Astronomical Union (IAU), 1946-1973.
Series VI: National Academy of Science (NAS), 1942-1973.
Series VII: National Aeronautics and Space Administration(NASA), 1954-1974.
Series VIII: National Science Foundation, 1959-1973.
Series IX: Publication Files, 1944-1974
Series X: Research, 1944-1974
Series XI: Trip Reports, 1958-1973
Series XII: World War II., 1938-1970
Series XIII: Personal Interests, 1965-1972
Series XIV: Photographs, 1940-1973
Series XV: Newspaper Clippings pertaining to Gerard Kuiper, 1942-1974
Series XVI: Oversize, 1911-1968
Series XVII: Slides, 1948–1974
Series XVIII: Films, Audio tapes, DVDs and filmstrip 1964-1974
Scope and Content Note
Papers 1894-1992 (bulk 1949-1973): This collection consists of the personal and professional papers of Gerard Peter Kuiper. The bulk of the material consists of his correspondence with other noted astronomers and scientists. His research including his work with NASA on the Ranger, Apollo, Mariner, Surveyor, Viking, and Orbiter Projects during the late 1950s through the early 1970s. Other items in the collection are his administrative papers pertaining to the Lunar Planetary Laboratory, publications; newspaper clippings; and photographs. There is also detailed account of Kuiper’s involvement as a member of the ALSOS mission in Germany in 1945 and the relationship between the United States and the Soviet Union following World War II.
Kuiper, Gerard Peter, 1905-1973; Sagan, Carl, 1934-1996.; Struve, Otto, 1897-1963—Correspondence; Hartmann, William K., 1962-1973--Correspondence.; Bok, Bart J.(Bart Jan),1906-1983--Correspondence.; Harvill, Richard A., 1905--Correspondence.; Oort, Jan Hendrik--Correspondence.; Rabe, Eugene K.--Correspondence.; Udall, Morris K.--Correspondence.; Oosterhoff, Pieter Theodorus, 1904-1978—Correspondence .; Solar system.; Atmosphere.; Planets.; Planetary Science.; Comets--Observations.; Asteroids.; Moon--Atlases.; Space.; Solar system.; Meteorites.; Project Ranger.; Telescopes.; Lunar photography.; Astronomy.; Outer space--Exploration.; Mount Lemon Observatory--history.; Yerkes Observatory--history.; Lick Observatory--history.; Catalina Observatory--history.; Kitt Peak National Observatory--history.; University of Arizona.; McDonald Observatory--history.; University of Chicago.; University of Arizona.--Lunar and Planetary Laboratory--history.; Pluto (Dwarf planet).; Mars.; Uranus.; Saturn.; Jupiter.
Container List
- Series I: Personal Files, 1924-1973
  This series is arranged alphabetically by subject. It contains awards received by Gerard Kuiper throughout his career, some bibliographies he created, personal calendars, a copy of his doctoral dissertation, program from his memorial service and the Dedication of the Gerard P. Kuiper Airborne Observatory. Two inventories one from 1924 and the other a list of books which were in his office when he died. There are also copies of the "Kuiper Philosophy" from 1942 through 1973.
  - Awards, 1948-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bibliographies, 1926-1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Calendars, 1965-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Dedication of the Gerard P. Kuiper Airborne Observatory, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Dissertation, Statistical studies of binary stars, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Inventory of books in office of Kuiper, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kuiper Philosophy, 1942-1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Inventories, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Memorial services, December 30, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Series II: Employment, 1933-1973
  Chronological. This series is arranged by year starting with 1933, and is divided into four subseries.
  The bulk of the documents are from Kuiper’s career at the University of Arizona from 1960 to 1973.
  - Subseries 1: Lick Observatory, Mount Hamilton, California
    - 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Subseries 2: Harvard University Lecturer in Astronomy
    - 1935-1936, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Subseries 3: University of Chicago, 1936-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 4: Yerkes and McDonald Observatories
    - Correspondence, 1949-1957 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Founding of Yerkes Observatory, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Yearly reports, 1945-1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Round Table, 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Staff Meetings (Department of Astronomy), 1948-1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - General, 1937-1961 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Subseries 5: University of Arizona, 1960-1973
    - Annual reports, 1941-1973 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Subseries 6: Lunar Planetary Laboratory (LPL)
    - Bibliography, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - General, 1962-1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Library, 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Memorandums to staff, 1961-1973 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - News releases, 1966-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Organization and Projects of the Lab, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Personnel lists, 1960-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Staff meetings, 1961-1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Symposiums, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Visitor’s log, 1963-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Sub-subseries 1: Communications LPL
      - General, 1961-1974 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - Unpublished issues nos.196-199 (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Unpublished issues nos. 200-209 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Subseries 7: Planetarium
    - 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 8: Department of Planetary Sciences (PLSC)
    - Proposals for Planetary and Lunar Studies Center/Institute, 1955-1962 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Proposals for a graduate academic program in Planetary Sciences, 1955-1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Proposals for a graduate academic program in Planetary Sciences, January 1955-May 1962 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Proposals for a graduate academic program in Planetary Sciences, June 1972-June 1974 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Teaching appointments, May 15, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Planetary Sciences Committee Meetings Minutes, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Planetary Sciences Courses/Curriculum, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1923-1974
  This series contains personal and professional correspondence and is arranged alphabetically by name. It contains both incoming and outgoing mail. There are also correspondence in the following folders: see also; University of Chicago correspondence, International Astronomical Union correspondence, National Academy of Science correspondence, NASA, Ames Research Center, NASA Apollo Project correspondence, NASA Comet Conference, NASA correspondence, NASA Ranger correspondence, Solar System correspondence, Stars and Stellar Systems correspondence, United States Air Force (USAF) correspondence.
  - Unknown (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Abbey to Aly (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Amand to Antelo (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Aoyagi to Avery (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Abelson, Philip H., 1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Abt, Helmut, 1955-1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ad Hoc Committee (Harvard College Observatory and the Smithsonian Astrophysical Observatory), 1968-1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Adams Walter S., 1931-1954 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Adler, Robert S., 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Agnieray, Alice, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Aitken, R.G., 1931-1943 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Akiyama, Mitsuo, 1963-1969 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Alden, Harold L., 1947-1959 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Alfred A. Knoph Incorporated, 1957-1966 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Alperin, Morton, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Alter, Dinsmore, 1955-1958 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1949-1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science (AAAS), 1968 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - American Astronomical Society (AAS), 1947-1959 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - American Astronomical Society (AAS), 1951-1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - American Astronomical Society (AAS), 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - American Astronomical Society (AAS), 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - American Geophysical Union, 1958-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - American Institute Aeronautics and Astronautics, 1964-1969 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - American Philosophical Society, 1947-1951 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Anders, Edward, 1959-1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Anderson, Leif, 1971-1972 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Annual Reviews Inc., Astronomy and Astrophysics, 1963-1973 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Archaeology Club, University of Chicago, 1955-1956 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Daily Star, 1950-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Arizona State University, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Armour Research Foundation, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Arthur, David, 1960-1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, 1959-1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Astronomical Society of the Pacific, 1956-1959 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Association for Higher Education, Meet the Professor, 1961-1962 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Astra Advisory Committee, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Astronarium – William Tully, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Astrophysical Journal, 1951-1963 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Association of Universities for Research in Astronomy, 1957-1973 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Baarslag to Baustian (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Beach to Bertles (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Bhatnagar to Bouwers (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Bowe to Bruwer (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Buch to Byl (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Baade, Walter, 1939-1956 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Babcock, Horace, 1953-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Baker, James G., 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Baker, Robert, 1951-1957 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Baldwin, Ralph, 1949-1965 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Bartky, Walter, 1948-1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Bashkin, Stanley, 1967-1968 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bauch and Lomb Inc., 1951-1966 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - The Bendix Corporation, 1957-1959 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Berland,Theodore, 1963-1967 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Binnendijk,Leen, 1946-1953 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Binder, Alan B., 1961-1968 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Blaauw, Adriaan, 1947-1966; 1973, (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Blanco Victor M., 1968-1969 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Bleibtreu, Hermann K., 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Block Associates Inc., 1963-1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Boeing Airplane Co., 1958-1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bok, Bart, 1929-1950 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Bok, Bart, 1955-1973 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Bowen, Ira, 1952-1962 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Bowling Green University, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Braun, William C., 1950-1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Bretz, J. Harlen, 1949-1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Brouwer, Dirk, 1935-1963 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Brown, Harrison, 1951-1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Brown University, 1964-1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Cabyeskii to Cayrel (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Cech to Colvin (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Comello to Czerny (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - California Institute of Technology (Caltech), 1958-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - California Institute of Technology (Caltech), 1958-1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Calvert, Mary, 1943-1954 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Canada, Alfred H., 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Cannell, William D., 1960-1967 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Carder, Robert W., 1962-1973 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Carl Zeiss Inc., 1966-1968 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Carpenter, Edwin P., 1939-1963 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Cave Optical Company, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Chamberlain Joseph W., 1954-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Chandrasekhar, Subrahmanyan (Chandra), 1936-1962 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Chicago Astronomical Society, 1956-1958 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Clemence, Gerald M., 1949-1965 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Clutz, Laurence S., 1952-1962 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Collier's Encyclopedia, 1962-1966 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Colombo, Giuseppe, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Columbia Broadcasting Systems(CBS), 1961-1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Space Research - COSPAR, 1961-1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Conference on Theoretical Geophysics, subcommittee, 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Connes, Pierre, 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Corning Glass Works, 1962-1967 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Convair Astronauts, Division of General Dynamics, 1962-1967 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Coyne, George, 1962-1973 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Croom, Herman L., 1960-1964 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Cruikshank, Dale P., 1960-1973 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - D.C. Heath and Company to De Montigny. (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Denver Public Schools to Dole. (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Domiques to Duverger. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Damon, Paul E., 1965-1971 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - David W. Mann Company., 1960-1962 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - DeConcini,Dennis, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Dees, Bowen C., 1956, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Dees, Bowen C., 1969-1973 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - de Vancouleurs, Gerard, 1950-1973 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - de Wiess, F.A., 1967-1973 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Dollfus, Audouin, 1950-1962 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Dollfus, Audouin, 1963-1973 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Douglas Aircraft Company, 1961-1966 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Dutch Academy of Sciences, 1949-1954 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Earth to Emery (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Encyclopedia Americans to Extraterrestrial (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Eastman Kodak, 1952-1966 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ebbighausen, Edwin G., 1937-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Edmonds, Frank N., 1949-1969 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Edmonds, Frank K., 1952-1962 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, 1959-1973 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Encyclopedia Italian, 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Federal Aviation Administration to Fischer (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fitzgerald to Fyter (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fagerstrom, Irene E., 1954-1962 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Feldman, George J., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Fernandez-Moran, Humberto., 1966-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Ferraro, John R., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Ferwerda, J.G., 1934-1936 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Fielder, Gilbert, 1956-1973 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fink, Uwe, 1967-1973 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Finsen, William Stephen, 1932-1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Focas, John H., 1953-1968 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Fortune, 1943; 1960 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Fountain, John, 1966-1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Franklin Institute, 1952; 1968-1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Frost, Edwin B. and Mary, 1896-1912 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Fujita, Yoshio, 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Gadomski to Gliese (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Godwin to Guth (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Gamow, George, 1959-1961 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - General Electric Company, 1949-1963 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Geochemical Society, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Gehrels, Tom, 1952-1959 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Gehrels, Tom, 1960-1974 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Gillespie, Carl, 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Goldberg, Leo, 1946-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Goldwater, Barry, 1960-1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Goles, Gorden, 1959-1961 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Goran, Morris, 1950-1957 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Gorter, Cornelis J., 1937-196? (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Grant, Gorden, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Gratton, Livio, 1950-1957 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Green, Jack, 1956-1972 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Green, Louis, 1952, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Greenburg, Milton, 1955-1958 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Greenstien, Jesse L., 1950-1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - The Grolier Society, 1941-1965 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Gross, Kay, 1950-1957 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Grumman Aerospace Corporation, 1965-1970 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Guerin, Pierre, 1964-1970 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Guter, G.A., 1965 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Haagsche to Haller (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Ham to Heering (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Heffer to Holiday Inn (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Holland to Hutchinson (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Haberer, Joseph, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Hall, Freedom F., 1962-1972 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Hall, John, 1960-1971 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Hardie, Robert, 1959-1963 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Harmon, Jack, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Haro, Guillermo, 1962-1973 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Harrell, W.B., 1949-1961 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Harris, Daniel L., 1947-1956 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Harrison, Wendell, R., 1959-1960 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Hartmann, William K., 1962-1973 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Harvard University, 1959-1971 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Harvill, Richard A., 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Harvill, Richard A., 1960-1965 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Harvill, Richard A., 1966-1973 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Hawaii Governor’s Conference on Science and Technology, 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Heckmann, Otto, 1947-1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Herbig, George H, 1951-1963 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Herget, Paul, 1951-1963 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Herring, Alika K., 1963-1973 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Hertzsprung, Egner, 1927-1963 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Herzberg Gerhard, 1946-1973 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Hess, Harry H., 1953-1961 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Hess, Seymour L., 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Hiltner, W.A., 1943-1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Hines, Dorothy, 1946-1951 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Hoag, Arthur A., 1952-1970 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hodges, Paul, 1950-1958 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hoening, Stuart A., 1961-1965 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Holsclaw, Douglas, 1967-1972 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Hooghoudt, B.G., 1958-1966 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Houston, Robert L., 1963-1971 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Howard, John N., 1963-1971 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Hoyt, David, 1972-1973 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Huffer, C.M., 1950-1957 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Huges Aircraft Company, 1961-1969 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Hunt, Mahlon S., 1961-1971 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Huzzen, Carl, 1958-1960 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Hynek, Allen J., 1946-1957; 1973 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - International Business Machines (IBM) to Iwanewska (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - International Academy of Astronautics, 1963-1973 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - International Geological Congress, March 22-29, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - International Symposium Center Remote Sensing, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Jepson to Just (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Java, Indonesia, 1929-1937 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Java, Indonesia, 1949-1959 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Java, Indonesia Bosscha Observatory, 1970-1973 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Jefferies, John, 1964-1966 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Johnson, Harold, 1951-1969 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Johnson, Hugh M., 1956-1961 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Johnson, Swede, 1964-1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Johnson, Warren, 1956-1960 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Jose, P.D., 1949-1951 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Journal of Geophysical Research, 1958-1967 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Joy, Alfred H., 1953-1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Kabisch to Kiwanis (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Kirkpatrick to Kwason (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Kaplan, Joseph, 1953-1962 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Kassander, A.R., 1959-1973 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Kennight, Charles E., 1959-1973 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Kent, Jack T., 1949-1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Kiepenheur, Karl O., 1945-1949 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Kiepenheur, Karl O., 1951-1971 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Kitt Peak Observatory, 1960-1973 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Klepesta, Joseph, 1960-1962 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Knuckles, Claude F., 1951-1953 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Kopal, Zdeneck, 1958-1971 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Kopff, August, 1946-1956 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Kozyrev, N.A., 1962-1969 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Kraft, Robert P., 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Krebs, Marlyn E., 1951-1962 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - L. Peter Cogan Foundation - Library of Congress (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Lick to Lyons (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Lamont-Hussey Observatory, 1951-1962 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Larson, Harold P., 1969-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Larson, Steve, 1968-1973 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Laufer, Arthur R., 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Lee, Thomas A., 1970-1973 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Leighton, Robert, 1950; 1958,; 1970, (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Lenham, Alan, 1955-1964 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Le Poole, J.B., 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Levin, Boris J., 1958-1965 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Life Magazine, 1948-1959 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Lovell, Bernard, 1948-1959 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Low, Frank J., 1961-1973 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Lowell Observatory, 1952-1972 (Box 11, Folder 12)